SACHIN

+91 8310339344 ♦ Bangalore, Karnataka, India

sachinyadlapure1993@gmail.com & LinkedIn & GitHub & Portfolio

OBJECTIVE

Highly skilled React Developer with 2+ years of professional experience in developing web applications using React JS. Strong understanding of front end technologies, including HTML,CSS and JavaScript. Passionate about creating user-friendly and visually appealing interfaces.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Mar 2013- 2016

The Oxford College of Engineering, Bangalore, India

SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3

Databases : MongoDB **API** : REST API

Frameworks : React js, React Native, Node js Express.js

Tools : Git and Github

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer:

May 2023 - Present

Codemodulo Technologies Pvt Ltd, Banglore, India

- Monitoring and improving frontend performance.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Supervise the production and maintenance of the user interface of websites and web applications.
- Implemented software changes and alterations based on design specifications.
- Deployed micro services in production and other environments.
- Integrated back-end with front-end systems.
- Contributed to the continuous development of a custom back-end framework.
- Created complex DB aggregations for data visibility.

Junior Frontend Developer:

Dec 2021 - April 2023

Pragati Softech, Banglore, India

- Plan and Design the Structure and design of web pages.
- Develop reusable code for future use.
- Supervise the production and maintenance of the user interface of websites and web applications.
- Assisted in defining and reviewing requirements and use cases.
- Fixed defects and performance problems discovered during testing.
- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Developed software changes and alterations based on design specifications.

PROJECTS

Jnurum (Codemodulo Technologies Pvt Ltd)

- Defined and reviewed requirements and use cases.
- Fixed defects and performance issues.
- Implemented and updated application modules.
- Technologies: React Js, Python, MongoDB.

E-Commerce App (Codemodulo Technologies Pvt Ltd)

- Defined and reviewed requirements and use cases.
- Fixed defects and performance issues.
- Implemented and updated application modules.
- Technologies: React Native, MongoDB, Node.js.

Crusher (Codemodulo Technologies Pvt Ltd)

- Defined and reviewed requirements and use cases.
- Implemented back-end modules based on requirements.
- Technologies: React Js, JavaScript, MongoDB, Node.js.

RMC- Mortar (Pragati Softech)

- This application is designed to provide end to end solution for Concrete Company where all work related and demonstration of workmanship worked under the administration.
- Defined and reviewed requirements and use cases.
- Fixed defects and performance issues.
- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Technologies: React Js, MongoDB.

Hospital-Management (Pragati Softech)

- Defined and reviewed requirements and use cases.
- Developed and tested APIs.
- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Performed data modeling for databases and storage entities.
- Fixed bugs under the direction of senior software engineers.
- Integrated payment gateway for donations to charity organizations.
- Technologies: React Js, React-Native, Node Js, MongoDB.

HOBBIES

- Playing Cricket
- Traveling
- Learning new technologies